Finding Aid for Robert D. Aldrich Collection
Bentley Historical Library
Robert D. Aldrich Collection
1783-1983
Bentley Historical Library
Aldrich, Robert D., 1920-1983
8516 Aa 2; AC; UAm
17 linear feet
28 oversize volumes
1 oversize folder
Papers and photographs collected by Robert D. Aldrich relating to the history, people and institutions of Concord village in Jackson County, Michigan; include correspondence, diaries, account books and other papers of Concord residents; records of Concord social organizations, businesses, schools, and church and governmental bodies.
The collection was received from Mrs. Elizabeth P. Aldrich (donor 2950 ) in May and July 1983.
The collection is open for research, except for negatives in box 17, which are restricted to staff use only.
Robert D. Aldrich (1920-1983), born in Concord, Michigan, worked for the Federal Bureau of Investigation. Throughout his life, he maintained and cultivated an interest in the people, organizations, and history of his hometown of Concord. He collected widely: manuscript, printed, and photographic materials, anything that related to Concord or to western Jackson County in general.
The Robert D. Aldrich collection consists of materials--manuscript, printed, and photographic--documenting the history of Concord, Michigan, in western Jackson County. The collection spans the period from the arrival of the first settlers in 1831 to the 1980s. There are a few items dating back into the eighteenth century (as early as 1783) since the papers of some pioneer families predate their arrival in Concord. The bulk of the collection, though, falls in the period since the Civil War.
The collection documents every facet of life in Concord. Included are the papers of numerous Concord citizens consisting of personal correspondence, diaries, account books and newspaper clippings about them. In addition, Aldrich collected the records of various Concord businesses and organizations, as well as some church, school, and governmental records.
The collection has been divided into two series: Manuscript and Printed Materials, and Visual Materials. Both series are arranged alphabetically either by personal name or name of organization, or by general subject area, such as Circus, Underground Railroad, etc.
Antislavery movements -- United States.; Arts -- Michigan -- Concord -- Societies, etc.; Banks and banking -- Michigan -- Concord.; Business records.; Concord (Mich.); Concord (Mich.) -- History.; Fire departments -- Michigan -- Concord.; Freemasonry -- Michigan -- Concord.; General stores -- Michigan -- Concord.; Horton (Mich.); Jackson County (Mich.); Michigan -- Social life and customs -- 1831-1840.; Michigan -- Social life and customs -- 1841-1850.; Michigan -- Social life and customs -- 1851-1860.; Michigan -- Social life and customs -- 1861-1870.; Michigan -- Social life and customs -- 1871-1880.; Michigan -- Social life and customs -- 1881-1890.; Michigan -- Social life and customs -- 1891-1900.; Railroads -- Michigan -- Concord.; Schools -- Michigan -- Concord.; Women -- Michigan -- Concord -- Societies and clubs.; Agricultural equipment.; Automobile service stations -- Michigan -- Concord.; Bands.; Bars.; Baseball.; Basketball.; Blacksmithing.; Business enterprises -- Michigan -- Concord.; Camping.; Canoes.; Carriages and coaches.; Centennial celebrations.; Children.; Churches -- Michigan -- Concord.; City & town life -- China.; Colon (Mich.); Concord (Mich.) -- Business enterprises.; Concord (Mich.) -- Churches.; Concord (Mich.) -- Dwellings.; Concord (Mich.) -- Panoramic views.; Concord (Mich.) -- Schools.; Concord (Mich.) -- Streets.; Courtship.; Dwellings -- Michigan -- Concord.; Farming.; Fires.; Football.; Fort Custer (Mich.); Freemasonry.; Hearses.; Hunting -- Michigan.; Laborers.; Lumber industry.; Mills -- Michigan -- Concord.; Mussey (Mich.); Parades and processions.; People with disabilities.; Picnics.; Railroad accidents.; Railroad stations -- Michigan -- Concord.; Railroads -- Michigan -- Concord.; Schools -- Michigan -- Concord.; Soldiers -- American.; Spring Arbor (Mich.); Streets -- Michigan -- Concord.; Swains Lake (Mich.); Underground railroad system.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.; Women.; Diaries.; Motion pictures.; Photographs.; Tintypes.; Billings, Hiram K.; Encke, L. C.; Keeler, Lewis.; Mann family.; Michigan Central Railroad Company.; Paddock, Alfred J.; Piper, William J.; Pomeroy, Austin.; Brucker, Wilber Marion, 1894-1968.; Malcolm, George A. (George Arthur), 1881-1961.; Townsend, Charles E. (Charles Elroy), 1856-1924.; United States. Army. Indiana Infantry Regiment, 36th (1861-1865); United States. War Dept. Citizens' Military Training Camps.
- Manuscript and printed materials
  The Manuscript and printed materials series is arranged alphabetically either by personal name or name of organization, or by general subject area, such as Circus, Underground Railroad, etc.
  Under the name of an individual in the Manuscript and Printed Materials series, the researcher might find biographical and genealogical information, marriage announcements, newspaper obituaries, and a scattering of correspondence. For some, there is more material, such as diaries for Hiram K. Billings, L. C. Encke, and William J. Piper, and scrapbooks for June Wallace Cory and Sarah Viola Keeler Tuthill. Of some interest are the files of Austin Pomeroy who served as highway commissioner and Jackson County surveyor, and papers about two Concord citizens who achieved national prominence, George Arthur Malcolm and Senator Charles E. Townsend.
  Organizational materials are among the most extensive portions of the Aldrich collection. These include account books, inventories, legal papers, minutes, and business correspondence for such firms as the Concord Telephone Company, the Concord General Store, the Concord Milling Company, the Farmers State Bank, and the Aldrich Insurance Company. The collections for Lewis Keeler and Alfred J. Paddock include both personal papers and records of their businesses.
  Governmental records include township assessment rolls and various files relating to village government. School records are extensive and include a complete record of District No. 6 from September 1866 to July 1911, including records for the school alumni association and memorabilia for nearly every school year from 1879 to 1952.
  Under the names of churches, the researcher will find histories, membership rolls, subscription lists, and collected miscellanea. Churches represented include the Methodist, Presbyterian, and Universalist.
  Among the various social and fraternal organizations represented in the collection are a scattering of records for such groups as the Concord Temple Association, the Pleasure Club, and the local American Legion.
  - A (Box 1)
  - Acker Family (Box 1)
  - Adair, Rev. J.A. and May Mann (Box 1)
  - Aldrich Insurance Company (formerly Chapple Insurance)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Policy Registers
      - Aetna Insurance Company, 1878-1895 (Volume 2)
      - Hartford Fire Insurance Company, 1905-1921 (Volume 3)
      - National Fire Insurance Company, 1901-1920 (Volume 4)
      - Phoenix Insurance Company
        - 1903-1929 (Volume 5)
        - 1910-1920 (Volume 6)
  - Aldrich, Robert D
    - Biographical Notes about Concord People (Box 1)
    - Concord History (Box 1)
  - American Legion, 1922-1928 (Box 1)
  - Armstrong, Walter N (Box 1)
  - Anonymous ledger, 1835-1840 (Volume 1)
  - B (Box 1)
  - Baker, A.M (Box 1)
  - Bamberger, Andrew (Box 1)
  - Band (Box 1)
  - Baseball (Box 1)
  - Bath Mills (Box 1)
  - Bean, St. Clair, Sr (Box 1)
  - Behling Saloon, 1891-1893 (Box 1)
  - Beyer, Mrs. A.E (Box 1)
  - Bicentennial, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Bigelow, Belle (Box 1)
  - Bigelow, Joab (Box 1)
  - Bigelow, Josiah (Box 1)
  - Billings, Hiram K. (Diaries)
    - November 1860-1861 (Box 1)
    - January-July 1862 (Box 1)
    - 1868 (Box 1)
    - 1869 (Box 1)
    - 1870 (Box 1)
    - January-May 1871 (Box 1)
    - 1872 (Box 1)
    - January-September 1873 (Box 1)
    - August-December 1875 (Box 1)
    - 1876 (Box 1)
    - 1877 (Box 1)
    - January-April 1878 (Box 1)
    - 1919-1920 (Box 1)
      (scattered dates)
  - Blackman Family (Box 1)
  - Blacksmith Shop (Box 1)
  - Blattner, Ralph A (Box 1)
  - Booster Day (Box 1)
  - Bradley, Addi Niram (Box 1)
  - Brown, Sidney S (Box 1)
  - Burt Family (Box 1)
  - Bus Lines (Box 1)
  - Business Directories, 1836-1919 (Box 1)
  - Businessmen's Association, 1940 (Box 1)
  - C (Box 1)
  - Cady, Charles H. and Mary Ida Mann (Box 1)
  - Cemetery (Box 1)
  - Census, 1840 (Box 1)
  - Centennial, 1876 (Box 1)
  - Chapple Family (Box 1)
  - Chapple, Lewis D (Box 1)
  - Chapple, Percy E. (Box 1)
    (see also Aldrich Insurance Company)
  - Chapple, William D (Box 1)
  - Circus (Box 1)
  - Citizens Mutual Insurance Company (Box 1)
  - Civil War (Box 1)
  - Clarke, Jennie M. (Diary), 1882; 1883; 1886 (Box 1)
  - Cobblestone House (Box 1)
  - Collins, W.S. & Co (Box 1)
  - Concord Centennial, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Concord Depositors Corporation, 1940-1943 (Box 1)
  - Concord General Store
    - Daybooks
      - October-December 1849 (Volume 7)
      - February-April 1850 (Volume 8)
      - May-July 1851 (Volume 9)
  - Concord Heritage Association (Box 1)
  - Concord Historical Society, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Concord Independent (Box 1)
  - Concord Milling Company
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Record Book, 1920-1925 (Volume 10)
  - Concord Motor Sales, 1937-1940 (Box 1)
  - Concord News (Box 1)
  - Concord Poultry Club, 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - Concord Roller Mills, 1913-1914; 1917 (Box 1)
  - Concord Stamp Club (Box 1)
  - Concord Telephone Company
    - Directories, Undated, 1956; 1978; 1979 (Box 1)
    - Financial Records, 1912-1982 (Box 1)
  - Concord Temple Association
    - General File, 1919 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 1919-1937 (Box 2)
  - Concord Township
    - Assessment Rolls
      - 1843-1846 (Box 2)
      - 1860 (Box 2)
      - 1862 (Box 2)
      - 1863 (Box 2)
    - Clerk's Statement of Money to be raised by Tax, 1905 (Box 2)
  - Concord Village
    - 1917-1919 (Box 2)
    - 1922 (Box 2)
    - 1924 (Box 2)
    - 1927 (Box 2)
    - 1931 (Box 2)
    - Charter and Bylaws, 1871; 1893 (Box 2)
    - Incorporation, 1871 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
    - Ordinances, 1973 (Box 2)
    - Pavement and Road (Box 2)
    - Street Lights, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Concordia (Box 2)
  - Congregational Church (Box 2)
  - Cory Family (Box 2)
  - Cory, Edwin (Box 2)
  - Cory, Israel (Box 2)
  - Cory, June Wallace, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Cory, Wallace (Box 2)
  - Cory, Mrs. Wallace (Adelaide Smith) (Box 2)
  - Couden, William (Box 3)
  - Cutter, Andrew H (Box 3)
  - D (Box 3)
  - Deaths, 1931-1959 (Box 3)
  - Democratic Ticket, 1875 (Box 3)
  - Detroit United Railway (Box 3)
  - Dewey Family (Box 3)
  - Dodes Family (Box 3)
  - Eggleston, Truman (Box 3)
  - Ensign, William (Box 3)
  - Entertainment (Box 3)
  - Encke, L.C., Diaries
    - February 25-April 24 1891, July 24-September 24, 1891 (Box 3)
    - September 1, 1898-January 16, 1899 (Box 3)
  - F (Box 3)
  - Fair-Concord Central Agricultural Society, 1876; 1879; 1886 (Box 3)
  - Farmers' Institute, 1900 (Box 3)
  - Farmers Mutual Fire Insurance Company, 1871-1938 (Box 3)
  - Farmers State Bank
    - Alterations to the Bank, 1963 (Box 3)
    - History (Box 3)
    - Merger with National Bank of Jackson, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1886-1969 (Box 3)
    - Mosler Safe Company, 1917-1918 (Box 3)
    - Reconstruction Finance Corporation, 1932-1934 (Box 3)
    - Reorganization of Bank, 1934-1936 (Box 3)
  - Findley Family (Box 3)
  - Findley, John W (Box 3)
  - Fire Department (Box 3)
  - Fires (Box 3)
  - French, Donald (Box 3)
  - French, John (Box 3)
  - French, Louise (Box 3)
  - G (Box 3)
  - Ganiard, A.M (Box 3)
  - Garden Club (Box 3)
  - Gibbs, Rev. and Mrs. William Looker (Box 3)
  - Good Templars (Box 3)
  - Goodrich Family (Box 3)
  - Goodrich, C
    - Account Book, 1834-1877 (Volume 11)
  - Goodrich, Mr. and Mrs. Levi N (Box 3)
  - Goodrich, William F (Box 3)
  - H (Box 3)
  - Hall Family (Box 3)
  - Hall, Roswell (Box 3)
  - Halsted, R.H (Box 3)
  - Healy, George Wade (Box 3)
  - Histories of Concord, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Horton, Michigan (Box 3)
  - Hubbard, Albert D (Box 4)
  - Hubbard, Stephen (Box 4)
  - Hubbard, Truman N (Box 4)
  - Humphrey Family (Box 4)
  - Humphrey, Luther (Box 4)
  - Hungerford, Frank (Box 4)
  - Hungerford, Ida (Box 4)
  - Hungerford, Percy Robert (Box 4)
  - Jackson (City) (Box 4)
  - Jackson (County) (Box 4)
  - Jackson, George (Box 4)
  - Jameson Pharmacy (Box 4)
  - Keeler Family (Box 4)
  - Keeler, George (Box 4)
  - Keeler, Grace (Box 4)
  - Keeler, Lewis
    - Anti-Slavery Materials (Box 4)
    - Business Papers, 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1835-1862; 28 folders (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1863-1875; 10 folders (Box 5)
    - Emigrants (Box 5)
    - Genealogy (Box 5)
    - Justice of the Peace, 1854; 1855; 1866 (Box 5)
    - Lewis, Nehemiah Estate, 1853-1854 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - Presbyterian Church, 1842-1872
      - Bell (Box 5)
      - Building (Box 5)
      - Correspondence (Box 5)
      - Subscription Lists (Box 5)
    - School District, 1843-1861 (Box 5)
    - Account Books
      - Cash Books, September 1838-June 1840; June 1840-August 1848 (Box 5)
      - Daybooks
        - September 1838-July 1839 (Volume 12)
        - July 1839-August 1840 (Volume 13)
        - August 1840-May 1841 (Volume 14)
        - November 20, 1840-January 4, 1841 (Box 5)
        - May 6, 1841-January 13, 1849 (Box 5)
        - January 16, 1849-December 9, 1856 (Box 5)
        - January 1, 1857-January 1, 1872 (Box 5)
        - February 14, 1878-December 31, 1897 (Box 5)
      - Inventories
        - 1835, 1839; 1840 (Box 5)
        - Undated (Box 5)
          (Solomon Wolcott Estate and description of land owned by Lewis Keeler)
      - Ledgers and alphabetical indexes
        - 1838-1842 (Box 5)
        - 1840-1872 (Box 6)
      - Lending Book, 1838 (Box 6)
      - Memorandum (Notebooks)
        - Undated, 1836-1838 (Box 6)
        - 1840-1841 (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
      - Travel Expenses, 1835-1837 (Box 6)
      - Wheat and Flour Accounts, 1839-1841; 1868 (Box 6)
  - Keeler, Lot (Daybook), 1834-1869 (Box 6)
  - Keeler, Dr. Louie N. (Physician's Ledger), 1878-1892 (Box 6)
  - Keeler, Dr. William N. (Physician's Daybook), 1854-1857 (Box 6)
  - Kellicut, Daniel A (Box 7)
  - L (Box 7)
  - Lewis Family (Box 7)
  - M (Box 7)
  - McGee, Frederick (Box 7)
  - McGee, Melville (Box 7)
  - McGee, Thomas (Box 7)
  - McKenzie Family (Box 7)
  - McKenzie, Carl (Box 7)
  - McKenzie, Frank (Box 7)
  - McKenzie, Thomas (Box 7)
  - Malcolm Family (Box 7)
  - Malcolm, George, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Mann, Charles Harvey (Box 7)
  - Mann, Daniel and Miranda Sears (Box 7)
  - Mann, Daniel Sears and Ellen Keeler (Box 7)
  - Mann, Henry (Box 7)
  - Mann, Jessie Ellen (Box 7)
  - Mason Family (Box 7)
  - Mason, Rev. A.W (Box 7)
  - Masonic Lodge (Box 7)
  - Methodist Church, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Michigan Central Railroad
    - General (Box 7)
    - Freight Accounts, March 1872-January 1876 (Volume 15)
  - Moelk, Henry (Box 7)
  - Mutual Protection Society (Box 7)
  - O (Box 7)
  - Opera House (Box 7)
  - Overy, Charles (Box 7)
  - P (Box 7)
  - Paddock, Alfred J
    - Correspondence
      - Miscellaneous Papers, Undated (Box 7)
      - 1832-1833, 1835; 1838-1839 (Box 7)
      - 1841-1858, 13 folders (Box 7)
      - 1859, 1861-1862 (Box 7)
      - 1863, 1866; 1868 (Box 7)
    - Account Books
      - Invoice of Goods, 1846; undated (Box 7)
      - Invoice of Notes and Accounts (Box 7)
      - Ledger (probably Carr and Paddock), 1884-1886 (Box 7)
      - Memorandum (Notebooks) (Box 7)
    - Cash Book (Carr and Paddock), 1884-1885 (Box 8)
    - Daybooks
      - May 1843-March 1844 (Volume 16)
      - March-October 1844 (Volume 17)
      - October 1844-May 1845 (Volume 18)
      - May-July 1845 (Volume 19)
      - July-November 1845 (Volume 20)
      - November 1845-April 1846 (Volume 21)
      - October 1850-November 1851 (Volume 22)
      - November 1851-July 1853 (Volume 23)
      - March-December 1853 (Volume 24)
      - April 1884-October 1885 (Volume 25)
      - October 26, 1850-February 26, 1851 (Box 8)
    - Ledgers
      - 1843-1846 (Box 8)
      - 1850-1852 (Box 8)
      - 1872-1882 (Box 8)
    - Cash Book, 1887-1888 (Box 9)
      (probably Goodwin Spring Creamery)
    - Ledgers
      - 1886-1887 (Box 9)
      - 1887-1888 (Box 9)
  - Parma Bank, 1934 (Box 10)
  - Parmeter Family (Box 10)
  - Parmeter, Dr. Jesse L (Box 10)
  - Parr, Jack (Box 10)
  - Philipp, Lawrence (Box 10)
  - Physicians Career Opportunities (Box 10)
  - Piper, Cora (Mrs. Truman H. Hubbard) (Box 10)
  - Piper, William J
    - Correspondence and Miscellaneous (Box 10)
    - Diaries, 1880; 1885; 1888; 1891 (Box 10)
    - Memorandum (Notebooks), 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Pleasure Club (Box 10)
  - Poff Milling Company, 1925-1928; 1931 (Box 10)
  - Pomeroy, Austin
    - Highway Commission (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 10)
    - School District (Box 10)
    - Surveys (Box 10)
    - Town Supervisor (Box 10)
  - Post Office (Box 10)
  - Pratt Family (Box 10)
  - Presbyterian Church, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Prohibition (Box 10)
  - Pulaski (Box 10)
  - Quick, Rev. Calvin P (Box 10)
  - R (Box 10)
  - Ray, Mark L (Box 10)
  - Reynolds, Albert W
    - Biographical Material and Correspondence (Box 10)
    - Daybook, 1875 (Box 10)
  - Reynolds, Jeremiah (Box 10)
  - Reynolds, William L.M (Box 10)
  - Rollins, William Meat Market, Daybooks
    - 1871-1872 (Box 10)
    - 1872 (Box 10)
    - 1875-1876 (Box 10)
    - Daybook, October 1872-May 1873 (Volume 26)
  - S (Box 11)
  - Sawyer Family (Box 11)
  - School
    - Alumni Association, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Athletics (Box 11)
    - Board Highlights, 1980-1982 (Box 11)
    - Building Dedication, 1953 (Box 11)
    - Classes of
      - 1879-1889 (Box 11)
      - 1890-1894 (Box 11)
      - 1895-1899 (Box 11)
      - 1900-1904 (Box 11)
      - 1905-1909 (Box 11)
      - 1913-1915, 1920-1921 (Box 11)
      - 1923, 1925-1928 (Box 11)
      - 1930-1931, 1937-1938 (Box 11)
      - 1944, 1946; 1952; 1981 (Box 11)
    - Districts
      - #6 (Stoddard District), Bonding, 1925 (Box 11)
      - #6, Record, September 1866-July 1911 (Box 11)
      - #8 (Mann District) (Box 11)
    - Fire, 1943 (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - Seeders and Weeders, 1945; 1954 (Box 11)
  - Sesquicentennial, 1981 (Box 11)
  - Severance, Albert Wallace (Box 11)
  - Simons Family (Box 11)
  - Smalley Family (Box 11)
  - Smalley, David (Box 11)
  - Spratt Family, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Spratt, Gardner D. (Box 11)
  - Spratt, William
    (also spelled Sprats)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
    - Ledger, 1783-1835 (Volume 27)
  - Spratt, William Harvey and Polly (Box 11)
  - Spring Arbor Township Records, 1833 (Box 11)
  - Stahley, George A (Box 11)
  - Stoddard, Jesse Blake (Box 11)
  - Stoddard, Samson (Box 11)
  - Swain, Isaac N (Box 11)
  - T (Box 11)
  - Taylor, James (Box 11)
  - Thacher, William F. Goodwin (Box 11)
  - Todd Family (Box 11)
  - Townsend, Charles E (Box 11)
  - Tucker, A. K (Box 11)
  - Tucker, William
    - Daybook, April-November 1884 (Volume 28)
  - Tuthill, Sarah Viola Keeler (scrapbook) (Box 11)
    (includes Tuthill, Dr. Frank S. and Tuthill Chauncey)
  - Tyler, Hamlin and Hannah, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Underground Railroad (Box 12)
  - Universalist Church, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Van Fossen family (Box 12)
  - Van Scoter family (Box 12)
  - Van Wormer family (Box 12)
  - Waldo, Frank H (Box 12)
  - Wetmore family (Box 12)
  - Wetmore, Henry A (Box 12)
  - Wetmore, William Chauncey (Box 12)
  - Whittaker, James (Box 12)
  - Winchell, Carrie Simons
    - Concord Heritage Association (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Universalist Church (Box 12)
  - Wolverine Muskrat Farm (Reynolds Lake Farm, Inc.) (Box 12)
  - Womanless Wedding (Box 12)
  - Woman's Tuesday Club (Box 12)
  - Women's Suffrage Petition (Box 12)
  - World War II (Box 12)
  - Zoning (Box 12)
  - Zuleski, James (Box 12)
  - Alphabetical Card Index (A-Z) (Box 13)
    (includes reference to Concord residents compiled from various sources)
- Visual Materials
  The Visual Materials series includes both photographs and motion pictures. The photographs include portraits of Concord residents, views of homes and of local businesses,churches, and school events and classes. The motion pictures are from the 1940s and are mainly of deer hunts.
  - Photographs
    - Agriculture, Miscellaneous (Box 14)
      (includes tintype of thresher and photo of steam tractors, farm wagons, and Concord Poultry Club)
    - Albion Center-photos of blacksmith shop (Box 14)
    - Ariss, Thomas A.-photos of home, Concord (Box 14)
    - Armstrong, Walter N (Box 14)
    - Arthur, James, family-includes photo of home, Concord (Box 14)
    - Baker family-includes photo of mock betrothal and tintype (Box 14)
    - Baldwin, Carrie (Box 14)
    - Bands (Box 14)
    - Bean family-photo of home, Spring Arbor Township (Box 14)
    - Bell family-includes photos of home and of woman in wheelchair (Box 14)
    - Bigelow family-includes photos of home, Concord (Box 14)
    - Billings, Hiram (Box 14)
    - Burdette family (Box 14)
    - Cady, Mary Ida Mann (Box 14)
    - Calhoon family (Box 14)
      (includes tintype)
    - C (various); includes Carr, Clarence; Caswell, L.-includes photo of home; Chapel, Caleb M.-includes photo and print of home Chapple family (Box 14)
    - Cogswell family-includes photo of home, east of Spring Arbor (Box 14)
    - Concord Baseball Team (Box 14)
    - Concord Businesses
      - Behling Bros. Garage (Box 14)
      - Bouldry and Tucker Grocery (Box 14)
      - Central Hotel (Box 14)
      - Farmers Elevator (Box 14)
      - Farmers State Bank-includes interior, 1918 (Box 14)
      - Gas stations and restaurants (Box 14)
      - Groceries (Box 14)
      - John Magel's Store [dry goods] (Box 14)
      - Michigan Buggy Company (Box 14)
      - Saloons (Box 14)
      - Undertakers-includes photos of hearse (Box 14)
      - Union Wind Mill and Livery Barn (Box 14)
      - Miscellaneous 19th century-1920s (Box 14)
        (includes general stores, creamery, barber, pharmacy, and cigar store)
      - Miscellaneous, 1940s-1960s (Box 14)
        (includes farm and industrial supply, and general merchandise stores)
    - Concord Cemetery (Box 14)
    - Concord Centennial, 1931
      - Carnival-includes photos of Ferris wheel and band (Box 14)
      - Ceremony and individuals-including Gov. Wilber Brucker (Box 14)
      - Parade (Box 14)
        (includes photos of boy scouts, floats, and covered wagon)
    - Concord Churches
      - Baptist (Box 14)
        (photos of remains after fire)
      - Methodist (Box 14)
      - Presbyterian-includes photos of fire (Box 14)
      - Universalist (Box 14)
    - Concord Fourth of July, 1898-includes photos of clown parade (Box 14)
    - Concord Gun Club (Box 14)
    - Concord Lions Club (Box 14)
    - Concord Police Department (Box 14)
    - Concord Schools
      - Album, 1914 (Box 14)
      - Classes
        - 1880s (Box 14)
        - 1890s (Box 14)
        - 1900s (Box 14)
        - 1910s (Box 14)
        - 1920s (Box 14)
        - 1930s (Box 14)
      - Concord Union School-includes classroom scene (Box 14)
      - High School [Union School] with addition (Box 14)
        (includes photos of fire)
      - Old Brick School (Box 14)
      - Old Stone School (Box 14)
      - School buildings, 1950s (Box 14)
      - Sports-includes football and boys' and girls' basketball team photos (Box 14)
      - Staff (Box 14)
      - Stoddard School (Box 14)
      - West Brick School-includes photo of George A. Malcolm (Box 14)